



## **Product Designer**

I'm a motivated product designer with strength in UX Research, UX Design, and software engineering.

I designed for creativity and love, aimed at bringing innovation and joy from ordinary. Currently I' pursuing my master's degreen of Information Management and Systems in University of California, Berkeley.



(669)-246-2810



jessie\_lyu@berkeley.edu



jessielyu.me

# Education



University of California, Berkeley Master of Information Management and Systems

Focus: Product Design | UX Design

Anticipated: 2020

#### University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign

B.S. Computer Engineering, with Honors Minor Mathematics 2012 - 2016



#### Dalian - IOS APP

Product Designer

June, 2017 - August, 2017

Dalian is an IOS application aimed at creating a new experience for users to digest news and information, featuring user-generated content.

#### LiveShopping - IOS APP

Product Designer

April, 2017- June, 2017

LiveShopping is an IOS application that creates an immersive worldwide online-shopping experience through live streaming provides a reliable and trustable platform for both sellers and clients.

### Experience



#### University of California, Berkeley

Graduate Student Instructor

August, 2018 - December, 2018

• Teach "User Interface Design" class as a graduate student instructor, focusing on instructing students design thinking, UX researching, and prototyping of software products.

#### Yahoo!, Inc.

Software Engineer

Jun, 2016 - July, 2018

- Worked in Yahoo Global Search team, implemented and launched Search Middleware platform which has millions of users each day on mobile/PC devices
- Designed and devloped an internal Search System debugging tool, significantly descreased trouble shooting time for engineers and editors by at least 1/3
- Worked as both designer and engineer to develop a Search UI configuration tool using React.js

#### Quicket Solutions, Inc.

Software Engineer

Sep, 2015 - May 2016

- Helped research, design, and implement UI of software for cloud based e-ticket system to help police officers more efficiently track tickets, warnings, and driver information
- Worked on product iterations, conducted contextual inquiries and usability tests
- Launched the application in many cities, named a finalist in Amazon's City on a Cloud Innovation Challenge 2015